

ALEN GUSINAC

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+46 793-260425

alengusinac.dev@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/alengusinac

github.com/alengusinac

Gothenburg, Sweden

TECH LANGUAGES











JavaScript TypeScript









MongoDb







Viie

EDUCATION

Frontend Developer Medieinstitutet

2022 - (2024)

Divemaster

Ouo Vadis Dive Resort

2018

Electrician (High School)

Viskastrandsgymnasiet

2010 - 2013

Emergency First Response Bartenderschool

HUMAN LANGUAGES

Swedish English German Bosnian

PROFILE

I'm a vibrant and enthusiastic 29 year old on the cusp of completing my studies at Medieinstitutet to become a future promising frontend developer. Already as a young teen I spent time playing computer games and even had my own game-server for Tibia when I was 15 years old that taught me valuable skills acquired through self-guided exploration of online resources. I always want to progress and learn new things so after spending 8 years as an electrician, amongst other things, I was ready to take on the next big challenge to be part of the promising tech industry. My education mainly focuses on JavaScript, with a few frameworks, together with HTML & CSS, UX/Usability, API-development, testing and design. If you seek a more detailed insight into my journey, I invite you to peruse my personal letter, explore my GitHub repositories, or connect with me on LinkedIn. You're also welcome to contact me by email and telephone.

WORK EXPERIENCE

10+ years

Frontend Developer

Nexer Group 2023 (10 weeks Internship)

- App Development (React Native) Demo presentations
- Agile
- API-implementation

Electrician

Alen Gusinac AB 2023 -**Tobias Söderens AB** 2022 - 2023 **Ecokraft AB** 2021 Elkontakt AB 2013 - 2020

- Project Management
- Logical Thinking
- Problem Identification and Resolution
- · Communication Skills
- Teamwork

Azure

· Learning and Adaptability

Underwater Photographer & Divemaster

Quo Vadis Dive Resort 2018

- Scheduling
- Safety Planning Selling Skills
- Big Responsibility
- Teamwork
- · Communication Skills

Bartender, Server & Cashier (Season)

Societen 2 summer seasons Björnvallens Sportkök 1 winter season Hotell Kittelfjäll 1 winter season

TECH PROJECTS









Live Site Code

Live Site Code

Code

Live Site Code



ALEN GUSINAC

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I'm slowly heading towards the end of my frontend development program at Medieinstitutet and I'm now looking for my first position at a company where i can take my freshly learned skills and implement them on real life projects.

Courses that I have completed are HTML & CSS, JavaScript basics & advanced, Graphical tools, API-development, UX/Usability, Testing, Work methods and Agile project. I'm mostly passionate about JavaScript/TypeScript and see myself in a position where I can progress my skills in that area. Also working in a team in this line of work is something I'm really looking forward to.

With me in your team you can be certain to get a passionate and social person who likes to contribute to make everybody feel part of a project so both colleagues and customers are happy with the end result. I'm very welcoming and have no trouble with getting to know new people. Creating a good vibe to my surrounding happens naturally as I'm very conscious that everybody comes from different backgrounds and have different experiences both in work and in life.

I'm a jack of all trades and my journey with programming started when I moved into my self built van and took off for Portugal to progress my surfing and was missing something to do between surfs. As I get restless, the search for something to fill in the gaps began. I turned to google to check for possibilities to study programming and quickly got hooked for frontend developing. I did some free online courses at FreeCodeCamp, Codecademy and started following The Odin Project. Later, I decided to pursue a more structured learning path and applied to the Media Institute, where I secured a spot in the fall of 2022 and have achieved great results in all courses.

One of my stronger sides is that I'm a quick learner thanks to my job as an electrician that has made me imply logical thinking and planing to faster be able to choose which road to take to reach my goals. If I feel that I'm repeating myself with a task, I prefer to spend some extra time to come up with a solution that can be reused to be able to spend less time and money in the future.

I am really looking forward to the opportunity to contribute to and grow with your organisation. Thank you for considering my application. I look forward to hearing from you soon and discussing how I can be a valuable asset to your team.

+46 793-260425

alengusinac.dev@gmail.com

im linkedin.com/in/alengusinac

github.com/alengusinac

ALEN GUSINAC